# Jeeva R

Greater Chennai Area



jeevasmart82@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/jeevasmart82



7200712356



https://jeevasmart.github.io/

## **Summary**

IT Support Specialist with over 3+ years of IT Support Technician experience as a Freelancer and I am currently employed as a full-time employee in a reputed company.

Having a basic knowledge of various AWS Cloud Services like EC2, S3, IAM, Route 53, and VPC.

I am currently responsible for providing all IT support such as troubleshooting, Level 1 support via phone/email/ Slack & portal to user queries regarding User's Desktop setups. My previous position made me skilled in providing end-user help desk support and I can remain calm in difficult situations.

Having knowledge of Linux Servers (EC2), and maintaining G-Suite admin Activities.

Tools: MobaXterm, Putty, WinSCP, FileZilla, VMware Horizon Client, S3 Browser Checkpoint Vpn Client.

### **Experience**

#### **VECTRA IT Support Specialist**

Vectra Automation, Inc.

Apr 2022 - Present (8 months +)

- 1. Provide Level 1 support via phone/email/Slack & portal to user queries regarding User's Desktop setups.
- 2. Installation and Volume Licensing of Big software like Solidworks, Catia v5, Inventor, AutoDesk, Siemens NX.
- 3. Managing AWS Services like EC2 ,S3,IAM,EBS Volume.
- 4. AWS server maintenance. Manage AWS HUB (ec2 instance) file system.
- 5. Manage and maintain G-Suite admin Activities.
- 6. Basic Office 365 experience, such as checking user access provisioning, performing mail trace, etc.
- 7. Monitor and support client PC accessibility (VPN or Anydesk) and ensure that they are always online.
- 8. knowledge of WinSCP and Configuration of a custom FTP server for data upload and download.
- 9. Coordinate with vendors to resolve vendor-specific issues.
- 10. Performing and Monitoring Remote Servers backup.
- 11. Endpoint Security, Firewall & Security devices management.
- 12. Provide on-site and remote support to local and international users (on demand).
- 13. Working knowledge of Windows Registry and ways to add/remove registry.
- 14. Take remediation actions in response to errors, problems, service requests and incidents.

#### IT Hardware and Network Engineer

#### Self Employed

Dec 2017 - Present (5 years +)

- 1. Installation of the operating system (OS) and Driver updates.
- 2. Troubleshooting hardware and software issues.
- 3. Unlocking and Flashing of all mobile phones.
- 4. Hands-on experience with Windows/Linux/Mac OS environments.
- 5. ISP Routers and Switches Configuration.
- 6. Installation, configuration, and troubleshooting of LAN.

- 7. Installing anti-virus software and removing viruses.
- 8. Network Administration: Static IP and DHCP Configuration.
- 9. Windows OS, Installation, Formatting, Partitioning, Configuration, and Troubleshooting.
- 10. Maintenance of CCTV cameras, unmanaged switches, and routers provided by the ISP.
- 11. Setting up and sharing network printers.
- 12. Troubleshooting and resolving client system issues.

#### **Education**

Kings Engineering College

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Computer science Engineering Aug 2017 - Aug 2021

Arignar Anna Government Higher Secondary School Higher Secondary School Certificate, Computer Science Jun 2015 - May 2017

Sri Saraswathi Vidhya Mandir Matriculation School Secondary School Leaving Certificate Jun 2014 - May 2015

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

- Trundamentals & Computer Networking Udemy
- Fundamentals of IT Helpdesk Freshservice
- G Linux Tutorial Great Learning
- in AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate (SAA-C02) LinkedIn
- in Google Workspace Administration LinkedIn

#### **Skills**

Amazon EC2 • IT Management • Software Licensing • Cloud Computing • Linux • Troubleshooting • Windows • Symantec Backup • Virtual Private Network (VPN) • Technical Support